shopmonk.com 2019-04-19

# Privacy Policy Global Business

This privacy policy **(“Policy”)** describes how Longman Capital Pte Ltd, having its principal place of business at 11 JALAN MESIN, #02-00 STANDARD INDUSTRIAL BUILDING, SINGAPORE - 368813 (“ **Company** ,” “ **we,** ” and “ **our** ”) processes, collects, uses and shares personal data when using this website www.shopmonk.com (the **“Website”)**. Do review the Policy to understand the procedure, purpose and practice with respect to your personal information.

1\. We understand that your private information is important for you. Therefore, we treat your private information with utmost security and maintain confidentiality with respect to the same, in accordance with applicable laws.

2\. This Privacy Policy **(“Policy”)** is an integral part of the Terms. For the customers based in European Union, the term personal information shall mean personal data as described in the General Data Protection Regulation in force in the European Union.

**3\. Why do We collect your personal information?**

3.1 We collect your personal information to comply with the legal requirements regarding collection of personal information in various jurisdictions.

3.2 The personal information we collect is necessary to provide our services to you. Should you choose not provide your personal information, you may not be able access various features of our Website.

**4\. Personal Information We collect**

4.1 Information collected by us relate to your personal details like name, or financial details like credit card details, or your address etc. The personal information collected are essential to conclude the purchase of products by you.

4.2 Details of information collected by us is provided at Clause 10.

4.3 The above information we collect includes combination of information we collect about you which identifies you as an individual. We use the information that you provide for purposes as responding to your requests, customizing future shopping for you, improving our stores, and communicating with you.

**5\. Consent**

5.1 We recommend that you review this Policy to provide an informed consent.

5.2 In certain jurisdictions, you will be required to provide an express consent. In this regard, you may please provide your consent by clicking on the checkbox below. For jurisdictions where express consent is not required, your continuous access of the Website shall be deemed to be a consent to this Policy.

5.3 You shall have the right to withdraw your consent at your sole option. In this regard, you may stop using the Website or send an email at [insert email id], informing us of your withdrawal of consent for accessing your personal information. Please note that the withdrawal of consent shall not invalidate the transactions, actions taken or any activity in accordance with the Terms which have concluded prior to the consent.

5.4 Laws pertaining to the minimum age for providing consent varies from one jurisdiction to another. In this regard, your consent shall not be deemed to be a valid consent if you have not achieved the said age. For instance, in European Union you should be above the age of 16 to give your consent for accessing your personal information. In the event you have not achieved the required age as per law, consent on your behalf may only be given a person who has parental responsibility of you.

5.5 You agree that certain personal information like your name, phone number, credit card details and address are relevant to provide the services to you through the Website. You agree and acknowledge that you are providing the abovementioned information to conclude the transaction concerning the purchase of the products and the said consent is freely given.

**6\. How We collect your personal information?**

6.1 We collect your personal information from various sources. The subsequent paragraphs of this Clause detail the sources of the personal information received from you.

6.2 **Information you provide:** We receive and store any information you enter on our website (the Website) or directly give us in any other way.

6.3 **Information collected automatically:** We receive and collect information from automatic sources like cookies, or and we obtain certain types of information when your Web browser accesses the Website or advertisements and other content served by or on behalf of the Website on other Web sites. More details on the personal information collected from cookies provided below.

6.4 **Information through mobile apps:** When you download or use apps/mobile website created by Longman Capital Pte Ltd or our subsidiaries, we may receive information about your location and your mobile device, including a unique identifier for your device. We may use this information to provide you with location-based services, such as advertising, search results and other personalized content. Most mobile devices allow you to turn off location services.

6.5 **E-mail Communications:** To help us make e-mails more useful and interesting, we often receive a confirmation when you open an e-mail from the Website if your computer supports such capabilities. We also compare our customers’ lists to lists received from other companies, in an effort to avoid sending unnecessary messages to our customers. If you do not want to receive an e-mail or other mail from us, please adjust your Customer Communication Preferences on the Website.

6.6 **Information from Other Sources:** We might receive information about you from other sources and add it to our account information.

**7\. Use of Cookies**

7.1 Cookies are small data files stored in your web browser. These data files are accessible to the Website. Cookies are required to provide a more personal and interactive interface to the Website. Certain functionalities of the Website like shopping cart may not work without the cookies.

7.2 The Help feature on most browsers will tell you how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie, or how to disable cookies altogether. Additionally, you can disable or delete similar data used by browser add-ons, such as Flash cookies, by changing the add-on's settings or visiting the Website of its manufacturer. Because cookies allow you to take advantage of some of the the Website website's essential features, we recommend that you leave them turned on. For instance, if you block or otherwise reject our cookies, you will not be able to add items to your Shopping Cart, proceed to Checkout, or use any the Website or Longman Capital Pte Ltd products and services that require you to Sign in.

**8\. Transfer of Personal Information to Third Parties**

8.1 Information about our customers is an important part of our business, and we are not in the business of selling it to others. We share customer information only as described below and with subsidiaries Longman Capital Pte Ltd controls that either are subject to this Privacy Notice or follow practices at least as protective as those described in this Privacy Notice.

8.2 We employ other companies and individuals to perform functions on our behalf. Examples include fulfilling orders, delivering packages, sending postal mail and e-mail, removing repetitive information from customer lists, analyzing data, providing marketing assistance, providing search results and links (including paid listings and links), processing credit card payments, and providing customer service. They have access to personal information needed to perform their functions, but may not use it for other purposes.

8.3 Sometimes we send offers to selected groups of the Website customers on behalf of other businesses. When we do this, we do not give that business your name and address. If you do not want to receive such offers, please adjust your Customer Communication Preferences on the website.

8.4 As we continue to develop our business, we might sell or buy stores, subsidiaries, or business units. In such transactions, customer information generally is one of the transferred business assets but remains subject to the promises made in any pre-existing Privacy Notice (unless, of course, the customer consents otherwise). Also, in the unlikely event that Longman Capital Pte Ltd or substantially all of its assets are acquired, customer information will of course be one of the transferred assets.

8.5 We release account and other personal information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law; enforce or apply our Conditions of Use and other agreements; or protect the rights, property, or safety of the Website, our users, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organizations for fraud protection and credit risk reduction. Obviously, however, this does not include selling, renting, sharing, or otherwise disclosing personally identifiable information from customers for commercial purposes in violation of the commitments set forth in this Privacy Notice.

8.6 It can be from the Website specifically or its affiliates or its partners.

8.7 Other than as set out above, you will receive notice when information about you might go to third parties, and you will have an opportunity to choose not to share the information.

8.8. We will take all reasonable steps to ensure that your personal information is protected and secure in the instance of any transfer detailed above.

8.9 Your information, including personal data that we collect from you, may be transferred to, stored at and processed by us outside the country in which you reside, where data protection and privacy regulations may not offer the same level of protection as in other parts of the world. By accepting this Policy, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing.

**9\. Information You may access**

9.1 The Website gives you access to a broad range of information about your account and your interactions with the Website for the limited purpose of viewing and, in certain cases, updating that information. Below are some examples, the list of which will change as our Website evolves.

  * As discussed above, you can always choose not to provide information, even though it might be needed to make a purchase or to take advantage of such Website features.

  * You can add or update certain information on pages such as those referenced in the Which Information Can I Access? section. When you update information, we usually keep a copy of the prior version for our records.

  * If you do not want to receive an e-mail or other mail from us, please adjust your Customer Communication Preferences. (If you do not want to receive Conditions of Use and other legal notices from us, such as this Privacy Notice, those notices will still govern your use of the Website, and it is your responsibility to review them for changes.)

  * If you do not want us to use personal information that we gather to allow third parties to personalize advertisements we display to you, please adjust your Advertising Preferences.

9.2 The Help feature on most browsers will tell you how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie, or how to disable cookies altogether. Additionally, you can disable or delete similar data used by browser add-ons, such as Flash cookies, by changing the Add-on's settings or visiting the Website of its manufacturer. Because cookies allow you to take advantage of some of the Website website's essential features, we recommend that you leave them turned on. For instance, if you block or otherwise reject our cookies, you will not be able to add items to your Shopping Cart, proceed to Checkout, or use any of our (including the Website) products and services that require you to Sign in.

**10\. Examples of Information We Collect**

This Clause provides broad details of the information collected by us, which should be read along with Clause 6.

**A. Information You Provide**

You provide most such information when you search, buy, post, participate in a contest or questionnaire, or communicate with customer service. For example, you provide information when you search for a product; place an order through the Website website or one of our third-party sellers; provide information in Your Account (and you might have more than one if you have used more than one e-mail address when shopping with us) or Your Profile; communicate with us by phone, e-mail, or otherwise; complete a questionnaire or a contest entry form; use our services; compile Wish Lists or other gift registries; participate in Discussion Boards or other community features; provide and rate Reviews; and employ Product Availability Alerts, such as Available to Order Notifications. As a result of those actions, you might supply us with such information as your name, address and phone numbers; credit card information; people to whom purchases have been shipped, including addresses and phone numbers; e-mail addresses of your friends and other people; content of reviews and e- mails to us; personal description and photograph in Your Profile; and financial information, including driver's license numbers.

**B. Automatic Information**

Examples of the information we collect and analyze include the Internet protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the Internet; login; e-mail address; password; computer and connection information such as browser type, version, and time zone setting, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform; purchase history, which we sometimes aggregate with similar information from other customers to create features; the full Uniform Resource Locator (URL) clickstream to, through, and from our website, including date and time; cookie number; products you viewed or searched for; and the phone number you used to call our number. We may also use browser data such as cookies, Flash cookies (also known as Flash Local Shared Objects), or similar data on certain parts of our website for fraud prevention and other purposes. During some visits we may use software tools such as JavaScript to measure and collect session information, including page response times, download errors, length of visits to certain pages, page interaction information (such as scrolling, clicks and mouse-over), and methods used to browse away from the page. We may also collect technical information to help us identify your device for fraud prevention and diagnostic purposes.

**C. Mobile**

Most mobile devices provide users with the ability to disable location services. Most likely, these controls are located in the device's settings menu. If you have questions about how to disable your device's location services, we recommend you contact your mobile service carrier or your device manufacturer.

**D. Information from Other Sources**

Examples of information we receive from other sources include updated delivery and address information from our carriers or other third parties, which we use to correct our records and deliver your next purchase or communication more easily; account information, purchase or redemption information, and page-view information from some merchants with which we operate co-branded businesses or for which we provide technical, fulfilment, advertising, or other services; search term and search result information from some searches conducted through the Web search features. 

**11\. RETENTION**

We will only retain your personal data as long reasonably required for you to use the Website until you close your account unless a longer retention period is required or permitted by law (for example for regulatory purposes). 

**12\. Your Rights**

12.1 **Access**.You may access your details by either logging into your account or contacting us at support@shopmonk.com.

12.2 **Opt-out**.Opt-out.At any time as per your sole discretion, you shall be entitled to opt out of all or any of the services provided through the Website. You may also opt out of the communications with respect to marketing, collection of personal information or sensitive personal data or information, any purpose for which we process your information which has not been intimated to you; transfer of your personal information outside your jurisdiction (in the case of you are a resident of country forming part of the European Union, the European Union). However, as stated above, opting out may affect certain services which we will be providing through our Website.

12.3 **Amend**.You may edit or amend your information by accessing your account or by contacting us at support@shopmonk.com.

12.4 **Portability.** You may move your information to any other service provider at your sole discretion.

12.5 **Erase and forget.** In certain situations, for example when the information we hold about you is no longer relevant or is incorrect, you can request that we erase your data.

12.6 Should you opt to exercise any of the above rights, please feel free to reach out to us at support@shopmonk.com. In your email you may please specify, the details of the personal information with respect to which you need to exercise your rights, the right which you intend to exercise. Please note that we will take the required steps as per your requirements within 30 days of the receipt of request from you. In the event the steps may take a longer time we will provide a prior notification with respect to the same. In order to ensure that your personal information is protected we will take reasonable steps to ascertain the identity of the person raising the request for exercise of rights under this Clause.

**13\. COMPLAINTS**

In the event you have any complaints regarding the use of your personal information in any manner, please feel free to reach out at support@shopmonk.com detailing your complaint. The said complaint will be resolved by a Grievance Officer. We will reply to your complaint within 30 days of the receipt of the same. We strive to resolve all the complaints to your satisfaction. However, if you are not satisfied with the resolution, you may subject to the applicable laws, may reach out to competent authority (for instance in the case of European Union, you may reach out to your jurisdictional Supervisory Authority).

**14\. CONTACT INFORMATION**

Should you have any questions or require any clarifications on this Policy, please reach out to us at support@shopmonk.com.
